<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-User_Guide-Product_Introduction">
	 <title>Product Introduction</title>
    
   <xi:include condition="exo" href="eXo_Content.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />

    <!--<xi:include href="Site_Publisher.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" >
      <xi:fallback xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
         <xi:include href="eXo_Content.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
          <xi:fallback xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
             <xi:include href="Site_Publisher.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" >
             </xi:include>
          </xi:fallback>
         </xi:include>
    </xi:fallback> 
    </xi:include>-->
	
	 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Product_Introduction-Site_Content_Structure">
		<title>Site Content Structure</title>
		 <para>
         While creating a site is a quick process, deciding what content to put into it and how to organize that content can take some time. Therefore, to make managing a site as easy and effective as possible, a site created with &PRODUCT; will always adhere to a specific structure:
		</para>
		 <mediaobject>
			<imageobject role="html">
				<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/sitecontent.png" format="PNG" />
			</imageobject>
			 <imageobject role="fo">
            <imagedata align="center" fileref="images/sitecontent.png" format="PNG" width="150mm" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		 <para>
			The Site Content is stored in collaborative workspaces of the underlying Java Content Repository (JCR).
		</para>
		 <variablelist id="vari-User_Guide-Site_Content_Structure-Details">
			<title>Details:</title>
			 <varlistentry>
				<term>CSS</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Files in this folder are used to define the presentation of your entire site, such as font, color, size and more.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>
			 <varlistentry>
				<term>Documents:</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						All the documents which are used in the site will be stored in this folder.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>
			 <varlistentry>
				<term>JS</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						This folder contains programming scripts used on the site. Resources in this folder help make a web page's graphics and navigation more animated and dynamic.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>
			 <varlistentry>
				<term>Links:</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						This folder stores all the links used in the site.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>
			 <varlistentry>
				<term>Media:</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						This folder contains three sub-folders:
					</para>
					 <variablelist>
						<varlistentry>
							<term>Audios:</term>
							 <listitem>
								<para>
									All sound files used in a site are stored here.
								</para>

							</listitem>

						</varlistentry>
						 <varlistentry>
							<term>Images:</term>
							 <listitem>
								<para>
									Pictures and other images used in a site are stored here.
								</para>

							</listitem>

						</varlistentry>
						 <varlistentry>
							<term>Videos:</term>
							 <listitem>
								<para>
									All video files used in a site are stored here.
								</para>

							</listitem>

						</varlistentry>

					</variablelist>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>
			 <varlistentry>
				<term>Web content:</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						This folder is used to store the documents which present the main site content (text, images, hyperlinks, audios and videos) of the site.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>

		</variablelist>

	</section>
	
	 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Product_Introduction-Web_Content">
		<title>Web Content</title>
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Web_Content-Web_Content">
			<title>Web Content</title>
			 <para>
            The <emphasis>Web Content</emphasis> is the visual or aural content that is encountered as part of the user experience on a website. It include any or all of the following elements; text, images, sounds, videos and animations.
			</para>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Web_Content-Web_Content_Structure">
			<title>Web Content Structure</title>
			 <para>
				Much like the website as a whole, ensuring Web Content adheres to a specific structure makes creating and managing the content more effective and dynamic.
			</para>
			 <variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Main content:</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
                     This is the key content, the text, images, links, tables, and other elements that make up the bulk of the web content.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>
				 <varlistentry>
					<term>Illustration:</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							This folder contains an image that is used as an illustration for the content. A summary also can be added to this image.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>
				 <varlistentry>
					<term>default.css:</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							This folder contains CSS data which is used to present the web content. CSS controls the layout, font, color, and more.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>
				 <varlistentry>
					<term>default.js:</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							This folder contains JS data which is used to make web content more dynamic.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>

			</variablelist>

		</section>
		

	</section>
	
	 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Product_Introduction-Terminologies">
		<title>Terminologies</title>
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Terminologies-Repository">
			<title>Repository</title>
			 <para>
				A repository is a location where data is stored and maintained. The content repository stores web content and related digital data and is accessible to users locally, without requiring content to be transferred across a network.
			</para>
		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Terminologies-Workspace">
			<title>Workspace</title>
			 <para>
            A content repository is composed of a number of workspaces. <emphasis>Workspace</emphasis> is a term used by several software vendors for applications that allow users to exchange and organize files over a network (the Internet, for example).
         </para>
         <para>
            In this case, the content repository consists of more than one workspace. The <emphasis>repository</emphasis> repository contains multiple workspaces, including: <emphasis>system</emphasis>, <emphasis>backup</emphasis> and <emphasis>collaboration</emphasis> workspaces.
			</para>
			 <variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>System workspace:</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
                     This workspace is used to reserve <emphasis>system folders</emphasis>.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>
				 <varlistentry>
					<term>Backup workspace:</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							The backup process depends on the timestamps of published content; each published document has a defined period for which it can be published and, when it exceeds that time frame, it will be automatically archived to the backup database.
                  </para>
                  <para>
                     This workspace is mostly used when utilizing the Workflow based content publication life-cycle.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>
				 <varlistentry>
					<term>Collaboration workspace:</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							This workspace allows users to validate and manage documents. This is the central place to store and edit contents and media.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>

			</variablelist>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Terminologies-Drive">
			<title>Drive</title>
			 <para>
            A <emphasis>drive</emphasis> can be understood as a shortcut within the content repository. It enables administrators to limit the visibility of each workspace to groups of users. It also offers a visual simplification of complex content storage arrangements by only showing the structure that is appropriate for users to interact with.
			</para>
			 <para>
				More specifically, a drive consists of:
			</para>
			 <itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						A configured path where the user will start when browsing the drive.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						A set of allowed views that could, for example, limit the actions available to users (such as editing or creation of content within the drive).
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						A set of permissions to limit the access to, and view of, the drive to a defined number of users.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						A set of options to describe the behavior of the drive when users browse it.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</itemizedlist>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Terminologies-Node">
			<title>Node</title>
			 <para>
            A <emphasis>node</emphasis> is an abstract basic unit used to build linked data structures, such as linked lists and trees and computer-based representation of graphs. Nodes contain data and/or links to other nodes. Links between nodes are often implemented by pointers or references.
			</para>
			 <para>
				A node can be defined as a logical placeholder for data. It is a memory block which contains some data units, and optionally a reference to some other data (which may in turn be another node that contains other data). By linking one node with other interlinked nodes, very large and complex data structures can be formed.
			</para>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Terminologies-Version">
			<title>Version</title>
			 <para>
            <emphasis>Versioning</emphasis> means that, at any given time, the node's state can be saved for possible future recovery. The action of saving is called 'checking in'.
         </para>
         <para>
            A workspace may contain both versionable and non-versionable nodes. A node is versionable if it has been assigned a <parameter>mixin</parameter> type <literal>mixin: versionable</literal>; otherwise, it is a non-versionable node.
         </para>
         <para>
            A version exists as a part of a version history graph that describes the predecessor/successor relations among versions of a particular versionable nodes.
			</para>
			 <mediaobject>
				<imageobject role="html">
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/node.png" format="PNG" />
				</imageobject>
				 <imageobject role="fo">
               <imagedata align="center" fileref="images/node.png" format="PNG" width="47mm"/>
				</imageobject>

			</mediaobject>
			 <para>
            Software versioning is the process of assigning either unique names or version numbers to unique states of the software. Within a given version number category (<emphasis>major</emphasis> or <emphasis>minor</emphasis>, for example), these numbers are generally assigned by increasing order and correspond to new developments in the software.
         </para>
         <para>
            At a fine-grained level, revision control is often used for keeping track of incrementally different versions of electronic information, whether or not this information is actually computer software.
			</para>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Terminologies-WebDAV">
			<title>WebDAV</title>
			 <para>
            <emphasis>WebDAV</emphasis> stands for <emphasis role="bold">Web</emphasis>-based <emphasis role="bold">D</emphasis>istributed <emphasis role="bold">A</emphasis>uthoring and <emphasis role="bold">V</emphasis>ersioning. It is a set of extensions to the Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP) which allows users to collaboratively edit and manage files on remote servers.
			</para>
			 <para>
				The protocol was developed to make the Web a readable and writable medium. It provides functionality to create, change and move documents on a remote server (typically a web server or "web share"). This is useful for authoring the documents which a web server serves, among other things, but can also be used for general web-based file storage that can be accessed from anywhere.
			</para>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Terminologies-Podcast">
			<title>Podcast</title>
			 <para>
            A <emphasis>podcast</emphasis> is an audio file that you can download and listen to on your computer or a portable MP3 player such as an <trademark>iPod</trademark>. The word itself comes from the combination of the words: <emphasis>iPod</emphasis> and <emphasis>broadcast</emphasis>.
			</para>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Terminologies-File_Plan">
			<title>File Plan</title>
			 <para>
				The file plan is the primary records management planning document. Although file plans can differ across organizations, their typical functions are to:
			</para>
			 <itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Describe the kinds of items the organization acknowledges to be records.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Describe what broader category of records that the items belong to.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Indicate where records are stored.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Describe retention periods for records.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Delineate who is responsible for managing the various types of records.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</itemizedlist>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Terminologies-Symlink">
			<title>Symlink</title>
			 <para>
            A <emphasis>symlink</emphasis> is a special file containing a reference to another document or folder. Symlinks can make it easier to access the specific target node that the symlink points to. In Content Explorer, a symlink can be identified by a small chain symbol next to its icon:
			</para>
			 <mediaobject>
				<imageobject role="html">
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/symlink.png" format="PNG"  />
				</imageobject>
				 <imageobject role="fo">
               <imagedata align="center" fileref="images/symlink.png" format="PNG" width="31mm"/>
				</imageobject>

			</mediaobject>

		</section>
		

	</section>

</chapter>