<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-User_Guide-Product_Introduction">
	 <title>Product Introduction</title>
    <xi:include condition="exo" href="eXo_Content.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />

  <!--  <xi:include href="Site_Publisher.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" >
      <xi:fallback xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
         <xi:include href="eXo_Content.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
          <xi:fallback xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
             <xi:include href="Site_Publisher.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" >
             </xi:include>
          </xi:fallback>
         </xi:include>
    </xi:fallback> 
    </xi:include>
  -->
	
	 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Product_Introduction-Site_Content_Structure">
		<title>Site Content Structure</title>
		 <para>
			Creating a site is a quick process, but deciding what content to put in the site and how to organize it will take a lot of time. Thus, to mange a site more easily and more effectively, a site always has a specific structure as follows:
		</para>
		 <mediaobject>
			<imageobject role="html">
				<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/sitecontent.png" format="PNG" />
			</imageobject>
			 <imageobject role="fo">
            <imagedata align="center" fileref="images/sitecontent.png" format="PNG" width="150mm" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		 <para>
			The Site Content is stored in collaboration workspaces of Java Content Repository (JCR).
		</para>
		 <variablelist id="vari-User_Guide-Site_Content_Structure-Details">
			<title>Details:</title>
			 <varlistentry>
				<term>CSS</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						This file is used to define the presentation of your entire site, such as font, color, size and more.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>
			 <varlistentry>
				<term>Documents:</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						All documents, which are used in a site will be stored in this folder.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>
			 <varlistentry>
				<term>JS</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						A programming script used on the site. This file is used to make a web page more animate and dynamic in terms of graphics and navigation.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>
			 <varlistentry>
				<term>Links:</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						This folder stores all links used in the site.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>
			 <varlistentry>
				<term>Media:</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						This folder includes three sub-folders:
					</para>
					 <variablelist>
						<varlistentry>
							<term>Audios:</term>
							 <listitem>
								<para>
									Store all sound files used in a site.
								</para>

							</listitem>

						</varlistentry>
						 <varlistentry>
							<term>Images:</term>
							 <listitem>
								<para>
									Store all images, pictures used in a site.
								</para>

							</listitem>

						</varlistentry>
						 <varlistentry>
							<term>Videos:</term>
							 <listitem>
								<para>
									Store all video files used in a site.
								</para>

							</listitem>

						</varlistentry>

					</variablelist>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>
			 <varlistentry>
				<term>Web content:</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						This folder is used to store the documents which present main content (texts images, hyperlinks, audios and videos) of the site.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>

		</variablelist>

	</section>
	
	 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Product_Introduction-Web_Content">
		<title>Web Content</title>
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Web_Content-Web_Content">
			<title>Web Content</title>
			 <para>
				Web Content is the textual, visual or aural content that is encountered as part of the user experience on a website. It may include other things such as texts, images, sounds, videos and animations.
			</para>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Web_Content-Web_Content_Structure">
			<title>Web Content Structure</title>
			 <para>
				The Web content may include various elements. Thus, to create and manage the Web content more effectively and dynamically, each Web Content also has a specific structure:
			</para>
			 <variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Main content:</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							It contains all key content such as: texts, images, links, tables, etc.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>
				 <varlistentry>
					<term>Illustration:</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							It contains an image that is used as an illustration for the content. Additionally, a summary also can be added to come with this image.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>
				 <varlistentry>
					<term>default.css:</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							It contains CSS data which is used to present the web content such as: layout, font, color, and more.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>
				 <varlistentry>
					<term>default.js:</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							It contains JS data which is used to make web content more animating and dynamic.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>

			</variablelist>

		</section>
		

	</section>
	
	 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Product_Introduction-Terminologies">
		<title>Terminologies</title>
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Terminologies-Repository">
			<title>Repository</title>
			 <para>
				A repository is a place where content is stored and maintained. The content repository is:
			</para>
			 <itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						A place where content is stored.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						A place where digital data are stored.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Accessible to the user without having to travel across a network.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</itemizedlist>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Terminologies-Workspace">
			<title>Workspace</title>
			 <para>
				A content repository is composed of a number of workspaces. Workspace is a term used by several software vendors for applications that allow users to exchange and organize files over the Internet. In our case, the content repository consists of more than one workspace. The “repository” repository contains multiple workspaces, including : system, backup and collaboration workspace.
			</para>
			 <variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>System workspace:</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							is used to reserve “system folders”.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>
				 <varlistentry>
					<term>Backup workspace:</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							The backup process depends on the published content timestamps, each published document has a duration for which it can be published and when it exceeds the timestamps, it will be automatically archived to the backup database. This workspace is mostly used when using the Workflow based content publication life-cycle.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>
				 <varlistentry>
					<term>Collaboration workspace:</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							Allows users to validate and manage documents. This is the central place to store and edit content and media.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>

			</variablelist>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Terminologies-Drive">
			<title>Drive</title>
			 <para>
				A drive can be understood as a shortcut in the content repository. It enables administrators to limit visibility of each workspace for groups of users. It's also a simple way to hide the complexity of the content storage by showing only the structure that makes sense for Business users.
			</para>
			 <para>
				More specifically, a drive consists of:
			</para>
			 <itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						a configured path where the user will start when browsing the drive.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						a set of allowed views that, for example, will allow to limit the available actions (such as the edition or creation of content while being in the drive).
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						a set of permissions to limit the access (and view) of the drive to a limited number of people.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						a set of options to describe the behavior of the drive when users browse it.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</itemizedlist>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Terminologies-Node">
			<title>Node</title>
			 <para>
				A node is an abstract basic unit used to build linked data structures, such as linked lists and trees, and computer-based representation of graphs. Nodes contain data and/or links to other nodes. Links between nodes are often implemented by pointers or references.
			</para>
			 <para>
				A node can be defined as a logical placeholder for data. It is a memory block which contains some data units, and optionally a reference to some other data, which may be another node that contains other data. By linking one node with other interlinked nodes, very large and complex data structure can be formed.
			</para>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Terminologies-Version">
			<title>Version</title>
			 <para>
				Versioning means that at any given time the node's state can be saved for possible future recovery and the action of saving called 'checking in'. A workspace may contain both versionable and non-versionable nodes. A node is versionable if it has been assigned a mixin type mixin:versionable; otherwise, it is a non-versionable node. A version exists as a part of a version history graph that describes the predecessor/successor relations among versions of a particular versionable node.
			</para>
			 <mediaobject>
				<imageobject role="html">
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/node.png" format="PNG" />
				</imageobject>
				 <imageobject role="fo">
               <imagedata align="center" fileref="images/node.png" format="PNG" width="47mm"/>
				</imageobject>

			</mediaobject>
			 <para>
				Software versioning is the process of assigning either unique version names or unique version numbers to unique states of computer software. Within a given version number category (major, minor), these numbers are generally assigned by increasing order and correspond to new developments in the software. At a fine-grained level, revision control is often used for keeping track of incrementally different versions of electronic information, whether or not this information is actually computer software.
			</para>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Terminologies-WebDAV">
			<title>WebDAV</title>
			 <para>
				WebDAV stands for Web-based Distributed Authoring and Versioning. It is a set of extensions to the Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP) which allows users to collaboratively edit and manage files on remote World Wide Web servers.
			</para>
			 <para>
				The protocol was to make the Web a readable and writable medium. It provides functionality to create, change and move documents on a remote server (typically a web server or "web share"). This is useful for, among other things, authoring the documents which a web server serves, but can also be used for general web-based file storage that can be accessed from anywhere.
			</para>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Terminologies-Podcast">
			<title>Podcast</title>
			 <para>
				A podcast is an audio file that you can download and listen to on your computer or a portable MP3 player such as an iPod. The word itself comes from the combination of two other words: iPod and broadcast.
			</para>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Terminologies-File_Plan">
			<title>File Plan</title>
			 <para>
				The file plan is the primary records management planning document. Although file plans can differ across organizations, their typical functions are to:
			</para>
			 <itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Describe the kinds of items the organization acknowledges to be records.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Describe what broader category of records that the items belong to.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Indicate where records are stored.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Describe retention periods for records.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Delineate who is responsible for managing the various types of records.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</itemizedlist>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-User_Guide-Terminologies-Symlink">
			<title>Symlink</title>
			 <para>
				Symlink is a special file containing a reference to document or folder. By using symlinks, you can easily access specific nodes (target) that symlinks point to. In Content Explorer, a symlink has a small chain symbol next to its icon:
			</para>
			 <mediaobject>
				<imageobject role="html">
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/symlink.png" format="PNG"  />
				</imageobject>
				 <imageobject role="fo">
               <imagedata align="center" fileref="images/symlink.png" format="PNG" width="31mm"/>
				</imageobject>

			</mediaobject>

		</section>
		

	</section>

</chapter>

